<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ludum Files</title><description>Lost documents on Game Crafting</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:00:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The first year student's Tiger Generator</title><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've thougt a lot about how to name that code generator. Indeed, it's programmed using somewhat bad practices, that shouldn't be used in a regular project. However, despite all its fault, this project possesses one of the most important properties one should expect from software: &lt;em&gt;it works.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="meetjoseph"&gt;Meet Joseph&lt;/h2&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-first-year-students-tiger-generator/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">844153bb-1af9-410f-90ac-0a07bef0e2b2</guid><dc:creator>kinokasai</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:16:42 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've thougt a lot about how to name that code generator. Indeed, it's programmed using somewhat bad practices, that shouldn't be used in a regular project. However, despite all its fault, this project possesses one of the most important properties one should expect from software: &lt;em&gt;it works.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="meetjoseph"&gt;Meet Joseph&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph is cool, Joseph is hip. Joseph is young. Joseph has dreams. Joseph is a first year student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph - in a flash of dazzling youngness - decides to write a Tiger Generator in Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="generatororganisation"&gt;Generator organisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a dash of thinking, Joseph decides to make his generator behave like &lt;em&gt;bison&lt;/em&gt; - a grammar-exploring program would do. A sequence of functions that would explore one of the many possible branches of Tiger's grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a variable declaration would be the following sequence: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;generate_code()-&amp;gt;generate_dec()-&amp;gt;generate_var_dec()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for a int expression containg a loop: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;generate_code()-&amp;gt;generate_while()-&amp;gt;generate_exp_int()[*3]-&amp;gt;generate_int()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="firststepprimitivetypes"&gt;First step: Primitive types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Joseph has no idea how to build a code generator from scratch. After a short moment of reflexion, he comes to two conclusions. First one is that all code is in the end only a sequence of letters, a string. The second one is the following: &lt;br&gt;
To build a generator from scratch, one must ask what the language's building blocks are. In tiger, those are terminals. Luckily, there's only two of them: &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;string&lt;/code&gt;. So Joseph builds functions to generate those terminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What's an int for the Tiger language?" ponders Joseph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Joseph might be young, but he knows that documentation is important.  Browsing the documentation, he finds the following sentence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Since the compiler targets 32-bit architectures, since it needs to handle
signed integers, a literal integer value must fit in a signed 32-bit integer" &lt;br&gt;
" - Ah ! Since we must reserve one bit for the sign, only 31 bits are available.
So an int is nothing more than a number between 0 and 2^31 - 1"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"But since I'm generating code, that is to say a blob of text, I must not
forget to stringify it."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for Joseph, Python makes it ridiculously easy to generate that with the random module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;max_int = 2147483647  
# Joseph is only a first year student, and while he's slightly ahead
# of the class, the aforementioned class hasn't got to pow() yet.

def generate_int():  
   return str(random.randint(0, max_int))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generating a terminal string is not much more difficult. Indeed, a random string in nothing more than a sequence of random letters. Python possesses a string containing all letters, &lt;code&gt;string.ascii_letters&lt;/code&gt;. To get a random letter, Joseph uses random again: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;random.choice(string.ascii_letters)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, he joins the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;def generate_string():  
    str_size = random.randint(1, 20)) # String size
    return "\"" + ''.join(random.choice(string.ascii_letters)
       for i in range(str_size)) + "\""
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to call them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using all its software development experience, Joseph takes the initiative to instantiate a globally scoped list of functions: &lt;code&gt;terminals&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;terminals = [generate_int, generate_string]  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then proceeds to build the wrapper function:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;def generate_dec():  
    dec = random.choice(terminals)
    return dec()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put the final touch to his Magnus Opus, his Guernica, his Mona Lisa, Joseph writes the main function:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;def generate_code(decnum=3):  
    code = ''
    for i in range(0, decnum):
        code += generate_dec() + '\n'
    return code

if __name__ == '__main__':  
    print(generate_code())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, exhausted by his work, Joseph falls asleep, knowing deep inside that, in the end, what he had there was a correct, parsable, bindable, type-correct generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="idgeneration"&gt;Id generation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph's first approach is using the same method he used to generate a random string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;def generate_rand_id():  
    id = ''.join(random.choice(string.ascii_letters)
        for i in range(8)
    return id
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that quickly makes code very confusing to read. Take the following snippet:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-tiger"&gt;let  
    type ezFEKfe { AEFIfdsE: int, ZFfseAZz: string }
    var ZEjFzPpD : ezFEKfe = ezFEKfe { AEFIfdse = 3, ZFfseAZz = "ezfizejfi" }
in  
    ZEjFzPpD
end  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really readable, is it? Joseph arrived at the same conclusion. That's why he decided to use another approach and use a &lt;em&gt;dictionary&lt;/em&gt;. Not a dictionary in the data structure sense, but indeed something akin to Oxford's. The dictionary data is contained in a simple text file, where one noun follows the other. At initialisation, the generator parses the file, and adds all the ids into a set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Tiger possesses three namespaces: one for functions, another for variables, and the last one for types. From there, there's two approaches. The first one is to duplicate trice the content of the set, to remove id from the corresponding set. Second one is to create three empty sets representing used ids, and on id generation, add it to the corresponding set. While more memory efficient, the second approach is gradually more inefficient for each id generated - and theoretically could take infinite time to compute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph, programming on his brand new laptop, /*add too much precision here */ chose to go with the first approach. His &lt;code&gt;generate_id()&lt;/code&gt; now resembles the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-python"&gt;def generate_id(set):  
    id = random.sample(set, 1)[0]
    set.remove(id)
    return id
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there's one check Joseph almost forgot. One must ensure that no keywords are present in the set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="types"&gt;Types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Joseph awoke on the second day, he realised his error. Indeed, he was striving to create a generator that could enforce type correctness. However, what he had built since yesterday had no idea what was a type. Having read a fairly long share of his Python book, Joseph decided to create a class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What's in a type?", Joseph asked himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His brain /* insert JVM speed joke here */, Joseph arrives to the following conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tiger, types are declared as records. As said in the documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Records are defined by a list of fields between braces in the following fashion: &lt;code&gt;type indexed_string = {index : int, value : string}&lt;/code&gt;
  and initialized in the following way: &lt;code&gt;indexed_string { index = 3, value = 'str' }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there's two sorts of types: primitive types and records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a type, there's a few attributes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The type's name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The type's fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that a type only possesses fields when it's not a primitive one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in a field - being only a tuple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The field's name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The field's type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having identified what would the fields of a Type class be, Joseph started pondering what methods would be useful. Despite his youthfulness, or maybe thanks to it, Joseph is quite pragmatic. He began by thinking about how he would use such a class. He came up with two examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First one's about primitive types:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;    int_t = Type('int', primitive=True)
    # Primitive types don't need a declare() method.
    int_t.generate()
    # desired output: `12312`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second one is about a record, &lt;code&gt;indexed_string&lt;/code&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;    indexed_string_t = Type('indexed_string', primitive=True)
    # How to add a field to generate ?
    # Add an add_field() method.
    indexed_string_t.add_field(Field('index', int_t))
    indexed_string_t.add_field(Field('value', string_t))

    indexed_string_t.declare()
    # desired output:
    # `type indexed_string = { index: int, value : string }`

    indexed_string_t.generate()
    # desired output:
    # `indexed_string { index = 124, value = "randomstring" }`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"A type must know its field. However, generating all the fields before creating the type could prove cumbersome, so I'll add an &lt;code&gt;add_field()&lt;/code&gt; to the Type class."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph's Type and Field classes' draft presents like that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;class Type:  
    def __init__(self, id):
    def add_field(self, field)
    def declare(self):
    def generate(self):

class Field:  
    def __init__(self, id, ty):
    def declare(self):
    def generate(self):
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id="typedeclaration"&gt;Type declaration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type declaration isn't really complicated. A declaration follows the following syntax: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;type type_id { field1_id : field1_ty, fieldn_id : fieldn_ty }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;#declare() shouldn't be called on a primitive type, no need for a
#special case.

#type_dec
def declare(self):  
    code = 'type' + self.id + ' { '
    code += self.fields[0].declare()
    for i in range(1, len(self.fields)):
        code += ', ' + self.fields[i].declare()
    return code

#field_dec
def declare(self):  
    code = self.id + ' : ' + self.ty
    return code
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id="typegeneration"&gt;Type generation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want my types to generate an instance of themselves."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type instance generation is a bit trickier than declaration. Contrariwise to declaration, &lt;code&gt;generate()&lt;/code&gt; can be called on primitive types, and must work recursively. Indeed, one of the type's field can be another record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing first, Joseph builds a draft of the Type class. It's supposed to work for primitive types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;   def generate(self):
       if self.id == 'int':
           return generate_int()
       else if self.id == 'string':
           return generate_string()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, his implementation works for primitive types. While the decision to hardcode &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;string&lt;/code&gt; behaviours may be surprising, it actually makes sense. Firstly, &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;string&lt;/code&gt; are builtin types in the Tiger Language.  They also are the first types declared in Jospeh's generator. So, it's impossible to re-generate an int or string type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a more down-to-earth way, that's also the recursion's base cases. Indeed, even when the type is a record containing a thousand records, everything amounts to a number of ints and strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;#field_generate
def generate(self):  
    return self.id + '=' + self.ty.generate()

#type_generate()
def generate(self):  
    if self.id == 'int':
        return generate_int()
    else if self.id == 'string':
        return generate_string()
    else:
        code = self.id + '{'
        # Joseph makes the assumption that all record will have
        # at least one field.
        code += self.fields[0].generate()
        for i in range(1, len(fields)):
            code += ', ' + self.fields[i].generate()
        code += '}'
        return code
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id="generationfunctions"&gt;Generation Functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph has added type declaration and generation to his program. But he never calls those functions anywhere. He hasn't even touched the concept of declaration functions. He decided then to build it's first structure.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;def generate_field():  
    ty = random.choice(types)
    id = generate_id(var_set)
    return Field(id, ty)

def generate_type_dec():  
    id = generate_id(type_set)
    ty = Type(id)
    field_num = random.randint(1, 3)
    for i in range(field_num):
        ty.add_field(generate_field())
   types.append(ty)
   return ty.declare()

def generate_dec():  
    return random.choice(decs)()

#First, primitive types
int_t = Type('int')  
string_t = Type('string')

# Types are stored in a list
types = [int_t, string_t]

# List of declaration generation functions
decs = [generate_type_dec]

def generate_code():  
    code = ''
    for i in range(0, 3):
        code += generate_dec() + '\n'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what's generated here is not correct Tiger. Indeed, declarations must be enclosed in a &lt;code&gt;let-in&lt;/code&gt; exp. However Joseph's only working on declarations for now. So he used a little trick to simulate a &lt;code&gt;let-in&lt;/code&gt; exp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language- language-python"&gt;def generate_code():  
    code = 'let\n'
    for i in range(0, 3):
        code += generate_dec() + '\n'
    code += 'in\nend\n'
    return code
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the resulting code is still not properly indented. For that, Jospeh needs an indentation module.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Welcome to Ghost</title><description>&lt;p&gt;You're live! Nice. We've put together a little post to introduce you to the Ghost editor and get you started. You can manage your content by signing in to the admin area at &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;your blog URL&amp;gt;/ghost/&lt;/code&gt;. When you arrive, you can select this post from a list&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome-to-ghost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">75c3c329-3c27-40ce-81a5-7d2844759f8b</guid><category>Getting Started</category><dc:creator>kinokasai</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 10:55:11 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You're live! Nice. We've put together a little post to introduce you to the Ghost editor and get you started. You can manage your content by signing in to the admin area at &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;your blog URL&amp;gt;/ghost/&lt;/code&gt;. When you arrive, you can select this post from a list on the left and see a preview of it on the right. Click the little pencil icon at the top of the preview to edit this post and read the next section!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="gettingstarted"&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses something called Markdown for writing. Essentially, it's a shorthand way to manage your post formatting as you write!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing in Markdown is really easy. In the left hand panel of Ghost, you simply write as you normally would. Where appropriate, you can use &lt;em&gt;shortcuts&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;style&lt;/strong&gt; your content. For example, a list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item number one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item number two
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A nested item&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A final item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or with numbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy some milk  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink the milk  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweet that I remembered to buy the milk, and drank it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id="links"&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to link to a source? No problem. If you paste in a URL, like &lt;a href="http://ghost.org"&gt;http://ghost.org&lt;/a&gt; - it'll automatically be linked up. But if you want to customise your anchor text, you can do that too! Here's a link to &lt;a href="http://ghost.org"&gt;the Ghost website&lt;/a&gt;. Neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whataboutimages"&gt;What about Images?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images work too! Already know the URL of the image you want to include in your article? Simply paste it in like this to make it show up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ghost.org/images/ghost.png" alt="The Ghost Logo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which image you want to use yet? That's ok too. Leave yourself a descriptive placeholder and keep writing. Come back later and drag and drop the image in to upload:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="quoting"&gt;Quoting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a link isn't enough, you want to quote someone on what they've said. Perhaps you've started using a new blogging platform and feel the sudden urge to share their slogan? A quote might be just the way to do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ghost - Just a blogging platform&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="workingwithcode"&gt;Working with Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a streak of geek? We've got you covered there, too. You can write inline &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; blocks really easily with back ticks. Want to show off something more comprehensive? 4 spaces of indentation gets you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.awesome-thing {
    display: block;
    width: 100%;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id="readyforabreak"&gt;Ready for a Break?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throw 3 or more dashes down on any new line and you've got yourself a fancy new divider. Aw yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="advancedusage"&gt;Advanced Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's one fantastic secret about Markdown. If you want, you can write plain old HTML and it'll still work! Very flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;input type="text" placeholder="I'm an input field!"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should be enough to get you started. Have fun - and let us know what you think :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>